# **Beatriz Accioly**

# Designer de produto

#### Resumo

Designer de Produto com mais de 5 anos de experiência em diversas áreas, demonstrando grande habilidade na solução de problemas e na compreensão das necessidades do usuário. Larga experiência em ferramentas de UX/UI como Figma, FigJam, Adobe XD, Miro, Maze, e em Métodos Ágeis, como o Scrum. Experiente na criação de wireframes, interfaces, Kits de UI e Sistemas de Design, contribuiu para a prototipagem de sistemas web e mobile, além de conduzir pesquisa de usuários e análise de feedback em suas posições na Outsmart Digital, Somos Claims e Stark Capital.

### Habilidades

**Avançado:** Problem Solving, Prototyping, User Interface, User Journeys, User Interviews, Human Centered Design, Figma, FigJam, Miro, Maze

Intermédiario: UX Writing, Content Writing, User Stories, UX Research, Mentoring, workshop facilitation, Ui Kit

Iniciante: Adobe XD, Sketch, UX Metrics. SEO, Product Roadmap, Design System

# Experiência Profissional

# Designer de produto

First Decision, Brasília, BR - Híbrido

12/2023 - 06/2024

#### **Core Responsibilities:**

- Collaborated on projects focusing on user experience, resulting in a significant enhancement of platform usability and user satisfaction metrics.
- Facilitated seamless communication between development and design teams, ensuring alignment with user needs and project goals.
- Implemented effective discovery processes and competitive research methodologies, resulting in a deep understanding of user behavior and market trends, driving informed design decisions and product innovation
- Collaborated and communicated design ideas which included specific features for prototypes to CEO/Founder, CTO, Head of Business, defining pain points such as icons to increase flow on platform features.

**Key Technologies and Tools:** User Experience, User Interface, User Journeys, Discovery, Research, Figma, Azure, Scrum, Facilitation workshops, Mentoring, Prototyping, UX Writing, Wireframes, Maze, Miro, User Stories

# **UX/UI Designer**

Outsmart Digital, São Paulo, BR - Remoto

03/2023 - 05/2023

#### **Core Responsibilities:**

- Collaborated with the design team in creating intuitive user interfaces and streamlined user flows, resulting in enhanced user satisfaction and retention rates.
- Facilitated seamless communication between development and design teams, ensuring alignment with user

needs and project goals.

**Key Technologies and Tools**User Experience, User Interface, User Journeys, Discovery, Research, Figma, Azure, Scrum, Prototyping, UX Writing, Wireframes

#### **Product Designer**

Somos, Belo Horizonte, BR – Remoto

08/2021 - 08/2022

#### **Core Responsibilities:**

- Led collaborative projects focusing on user experience, resulting in a significant enhancement of platform usability and user satisfaction metrics.
- Facilitated seamless communication between development and design teams, ensuring alignment with user needs and project goals.
- Implemented effective discovery processes and competitive research methodologies, resulting in a deep understanding of user behavior and market trends, driving informed design decisions and product innovations.

**Key Technologies and Tools:** User Experience, User Interface, User Journeys, Discovery, Research, Figma, Azure, Scrum, Facilitation workshops, Mentoring, Prototyping, UX Writing, Wireframes

#### **Role Here**

Stark Capital, São Paulo, BR - Remote

10/2020 to 03/2021

#### **Core Responsibilities:**

- Designed and implemented user-centric interfaces and user flows, leading to a marked improvement in user engagement and conversion rates.
- Established a robust UI Kit and Design System, enhancing design consistency and scalability across the organization's digital products.
- Provided critical front-end programming support, fostering seamless collaboration between design and development, resulting in expedited project delivery and improved product quality.

**Key Technologies and Tools:** User Experience, User Interface, User Journeys, Figma, Scrum,, Prototyping, UX Writing, Wireframes, HTML, CSS, React

# Educação

#### Bacharelado em Design Gráfico

Centro Universitário Senac, São Paulo, BR

07/2012 - 01/2017

• Relevant coursework: Typography, Packaging, Editorial Design, Illustration, Interaction Design, Projects

#### Técnologo em Análise e Desenvolvimento de sistemas

BandTec, São Paulo, BR

07/2018 - 01/2020

• Relevant coursework: Programming Logic, Database. Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Software Architecture, Data Structures, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Project Management

# **Idiomas**

Português: Nativo Inglês: Fluente